# DAVID COLE

# **Front End Developer**

Address:

2566 Sherbrooke Ouest, Montreal H4A 1H3

Phone:

+1 (607) 214 0085

**Email:** 

davidcole715@protonmail.com

## **Summary**

Senior Web Front End Developer specializing in front end development. In 10-plus years of Front-End experience, experienced with all stages of the development cycle for web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including React, Node, JavaScript, CSS, MySQL. Strong background in project management and customer relations. Completed over 80 projects in Montreal with costs ranging from 50\$ to 7300\$.

#### **Skills**

- Knowledgeable in User Interface/ User Experience
- SEO Best Practices
- JavaScript
- CSS and JS Frameworks
- CSS Preprocessors
- AngularJS
- ReactJS
- NodeJS
- Vue.is
- Creative design

- Innovative
- Service-focused
- Server-Side Rendering Python (Django, Flask, Fast API) Payment/Email/SMS/Live
- Streaming/Push Notification SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL, NoSQL) Google Firebase
- Social Platforms integration (Google, Facebook, Instagram, TikTok, YouTube)
- GCP(Authentication)
   Docker/Kubernetes/Jenkins Teamwork

# **Experience**

Team Leader – 02/2023 - Present

#### Montreal, Canada

- Recorded a team of 8 React developers, collaborating seamlessly with cross-functional teams to deliver cutting-edge web applications
- Trained and mentored a team of 4 in front-end development, equipping them with essential skills to
  create responsive web designs and increasing team productivity by 40% through ongoing coaching and
  code reviews.

**React Developer** - 03/2022 - 01/2023

#### East Azerbaijan, Iran

- Headed the development of a web application and website using React, resulting in a seamless user experience and increased website traffic by 40%
- Applied performance tuning techniques on stored procedures and back-end queries which resulted in 46% improvement in application performance

# **DAVID COLE**

## **Front End Developer**

Address:

2566 Sherbrooke Ouest, Montreal H4A 1H3

Phone:

+1 (607) 214 0085

**Email:** 

jessgrant715@protonmail.com

#### Senior Front End Developer - 12/2019 - 01/2022 Montreal, Canada

- Engineered a highly intuitive and user-friendly client dashboard equipped with real-time analytics and interactive features
- Directed cross-functional collaboration between UX/UI design teams, driving a comprehensive website and application improvement initiative that delivered a substantial 25% boost in conversion rates and revenue.
- Daily maintenance of code, debugging issues and solving clients' problems
- Presented findings in a clear and concise manner to key decision-makers

## **React Developer** - 03/2016 - 08/2019

#### Montreal, Canada

- Developed and maintained highly responsive user interfaces for 10+ web applications, utilizing React, Redux, TypeScript, and Material-UI; optimized UI/UX resulting in a 40% increase in user engagement and a 20% decrease in bounce rate.
- Orchestrated seamless teamwork with UX designers, product managers, and developers to successfully
  deliver user-friendly and responsive web solutions; improved conversion rate by 15% and achieved a 20%
  increase in customer satisfaction
- Integrated RESTful APIs and WebSocket connections to enable real-time data updates and notifications, resulting in a 40% reduction
- Engineered innovative processes and technologies that streamlined operations, reducing time-to-market by 30% and enabling the team to successfully deliver 50+ client projects on time and within budget.

#### **Education**

Bachelor of Science: Computer Information Systems - 2015

Yukon University, YT

# Languages

English - C2

### **Certifications**

PHP Framework (certificate): **Zend, Codelgniter, Symfony**.

Programming Languages: React, NodeJS, HTML5, PHP OOP, CSS, SQL, MySQL.